http://www.lungevity.org/about-us/privacy-policy

Jump to navigation
You are hereHome › About Us ›
Privacy Policy
LUNGevity Foundation has created this Privacy Policy to explain why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy within our website. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the website located at the URL LUNGevity.org and the LUNGevity Lung Cancer Navigator mobile application.
In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy. LUNGevity Foundation reserves the right at any time and without notice to change this Privacy Policy simply by posting such changes on our website. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting.
Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, this Privacy Policy notifies you of:
What information of yours is collected through the website and mobile applications and how it is used;
How such information is protected;
With whom your information may be shared;
How you can contact us to review the personal information collected and request corrections; and
How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information.
Questions regarding this policy should be directed to LUNGevity Foundation by sending an email to info@lungevity.org. Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line.
What Information We Collect and How it is Used
Donor Information
Donor information is stored in a remotely hosted database and is never made available to third parties. The Foundation uses reasonable precautions to keep all personal information secure. LUNGevity Foundation cannot be held liable or responsible for a security breach by a third party, and your continued use of this website implies that you agree to this statement.
Additionally, you have the option of receiving information from LUNGevity Foundation concerning our programs and donation opportunities. You may opt out of receiving this information at any time. LUNGevity Foundation does not sell or rent the personal information we collect from our online donors.
Medical Information
Our LUNGevity Lung Cancer Navigator mobile application allows users to enter their personal contact information, information about a lung cancer diagnosis and treatments and side effects, and contact information for caregivers and other members of the care team.
Personal and Financial Information
Our registration forms and our Breathe Deep mobile applicationrequire users to give us contact information that may include name, email address, format preference (HTML vs. text), address, interests, and similar information. If you pay to register for an event, or if you make a donation, we request other sensitive information from our visitors, such as birth dates and credit card numbers.
Credit Card and Personal Information Security
All information provided to LUNGevity Foundation is transmitted using TLS/SSL (Transport Layer Security/Secure Sockets Layer) encryption. TLS/SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. Online donations and other financial transactions completed through our website are processed by third-party credit card processors and are PCI DSS compliant. PCI DSS is the payment card industry security requirement for entities that store, process, or transmit cardholder data, and has been endorsed by all the major card brands—Visa Inc., MasterCard Worldwide, Discover Network, American Express, and JCB. PCI DSS compliance gives consumers the confidence they need to know that organizations accepting electronic payments or donations are doing so in a verified, secure, and consistent fashion. The processes, procedures, network configuration, and overall environment used to process your financial support of our organization have met the stringent guidelines of a third-party audit and are in compliance with the high standards set by the industry. This comprehensive standard is intended to help organizations such as ours proactively protect your account data, a responsibility we take very seriously. We also protect account information by storing it in a secure third-party database that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of LUNGevity Foundation.
Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information.
Internet Protocol Address
We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users' movements within the site, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the Site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Use of "Cookies"
Our Site uses cookies to enhance your experience while using it. Cookies are pieces of information that some websites transfer to the computer that is browsing that website and are used for record-keeping purposes. Use of cookies makes web surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords and your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular website. Cookies are considered to be an industry standard.
Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. If you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. Please note, though, that if you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, some areas of our Site may not function properly when you view them.
Other Websites
Our Site and mobile apps contain links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which LUNGevity Foundation has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different from ours.
Sharing of Personal Information
LUNGevity Foundation does not sell or rent the personal information we collect from our online registrations or donations, nor do we share it outside of our organization. Contact information for event participants may be shared with LUNGevity’s Event Coordinators. Event Coordinators are bound by contract to keep that information confidential. Some forms on the website optionally allow people with lung cancer to provide information about their diagnosis and treatment; such information is shared only with LUNGevity’s staff and remains confidential.
LUNGevity Foundation reserves the right to change its policy concerning the sharing of personal information. If you do not want your personal information shared outside of our organization, you may send us written notice either by mail or by email to the address below, and all access to your personal information will be restricted.
Offline Donations
LUNGevity Foundation will not trade, share, or sell any donor’s personal information with anyone else, nor send donors mailings on behalf of other organizations. This applies to all donors regardless of whether they donate online, in person, by mail, or by phone.
Reviewing Personal Information Collected and Requesting Corrections and/or Removal
When you make any transaction on our website (including registering for an event or making a donation) or register as a user of one of our mobile apps, you create a user name and password. With that information you can log on to our Site or the app and update your profile, which will allow you to review and correct the personal information we have on file for you. You may also contact us as shown below to remove your name and information from our system.
Contacting Us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this organization, or your dealings with this Site, please contact:
LUNGevity Foundation
PO Box 754
Chicago, IL 60690
Phone: 312.407.6100  |  Fax: 312.464.0737
info@lungevity.org
For Patients & CaregiversCOVID-19 and Lung CancerWeekly COVID-19 UpdatesFrequently Asked COVID-19 QuestionsConversations with Healthcare ExpertsSelf-care for Patients and CaregiversCOVID-19 Policy InitiativesFinancial Assistance During COVID-19Help with MedicationsCOVID-19 GlossaryInformación sobre coronavirus en españolLung Cancer 101Recently DiagnosedHow Lung Cancer DevelopsReducing Your RiskScreening & Early DetectionSigns & SymptomsDiagnosing Lung CancerTypes of Lung CancerLung Cancer StagingYour Medical TeamTreatment OptionsFind a Clinical TrialAsking the Right QuestionsQuestions to Ask Your Healthcare ProfessionalsChecklistsSupport ServicesLung Cancer Support CommunityLunch & LearnsLung Cancer HELPLinePeer-to-Peer MentoringSurvivorship ConferencesVirtual MeetupsOnline CommunitiesMeet Ina®, Your Personal Intelligent Nutrition AssistantSurvivor Resource CenterLiving Well With Lung CancerEmotional SupportPractical SupportSurvivor StoriesResourcesCaregiver Resource CenterRole of the CaregiverEnd-of-Life PlanningCaregiving TipsResources for CaregiversCOPE SummitLung Cancer Navigator Mobile AppGet Educational MaterialsMore Resources for Patients & CaregiversVideo and Webinar LibraryGlossaryFor Supporters & Advocates#ChangeLungCancer GallerySupport Our WorkDonate NowHonor/Memorial DonationPlanned GivingTribute FundsOther Ways to GiveShop for a CauseVolunteerSocial MediaSocial Media Volunteer ProgramLung Cancer StatisticsGet Educational MaterialsLung Cancer AwarenessLUNGevity Action NetworkOur ResearchTranslational Science Research Grant ProgramsEarly DetectionTargeted TherapeuticsCareer Development Award ProgramStand Up To Cancer - Interception Research2021 EGFR-Positive Research Award2020 ALK-Positive Research AwardApplying for a LUNGevity GrantFunded ProjectsImpact of LUNGevity ResearchPatient-Focused Research Center (Patient FoRCe)Patient Preferences and Patient ExperienceShared Decision MakingBarriers to Optimal CarePatient FoRCe External Advisory CommitteeHelp Drive Lung Cancer ResearchHow You Can Help Fund ResearchPublic PolicyAccess to Clinical TrialsAccess to Biomarker TestingComment & Sign-on LettersAdvisory BoardsCollaborations & PartnershipsLung Cancer ScorecardEventsBreathe DeepTeam LUNGevity Endurance EventsSurvivorship ConferencesGalas & Special EventsNational Celebration of HopeNational Celebration of Hope SponsorshipDIY EventsNews & BlogsBlogsMedia ReleasesNewsletter ArchiveLUNGevity in the NewsLung Cancer in the NewsShare Your StoryTell Me Something GoodAbout UsOur ImpactImpact ReportOur PeopleBoard of DirectorsSenior ManagementScientific Advisory BoardHonorary Leadership BoardMission, Vision, & HistoryCollaborations & PartnershipsLUNGevity PublicationsAdvisory BoardsMedia ResourcesMedia KitFinancial & Legal DisclosuresContact Us
Menu
LUNGevity Foundation
CONTACT US
CHICAGO OFFICE
PO Box 754
Chicago, IL 60690
Phone: 312.407.6100
Fax: 312.464.0737
CFC#12970
This website is not intended to, and does not, provide medical advice, professional diagnosis, opinion, treatment, or services. Medical information provided on this site is for informational and educational purposes only. After reading content from this website, you are encouraged to review the information carefully with your physician.
Privacy policy
© 2020 LUNGevity Foundation. All rights reserved.
Log in   Log out
